### CHUA ZHENG TAT

zhengtat@tatwritescode.com | Singapore | github.com/ztcjoe93 | +65 9003 1630 | www.tatwritescode.com

#### **EXECUTIVE SUMMARY**

Software Developer who loves and embraces the FOSS concept, responsible for L2/L3 support, software deliverables and building new solutions with cloud resources such as AWS. Passionate at learning new technologies and advocates utilizing technology to make a difference.

Experienced with tech operations, Level 2/3 Support, SDLC and the AGILE methodology. Proficient in Linux system administration, and possesses scripting knowledge in Python, Bash and Golang. Likes to talk technology as though it's major league gaming.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: Java, Python, Golang, SQL, Bash, Javascript

**Frameworks, Software & Services**: Flask, Selenium, Flutter, React, Git, NodeJS, Cucumber, MySQL, Terraform, GitLab, Ansible, Spring Boot, Vim, AWS, Docker

OSes: Windows, Linux

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

S&P Global 2021-06 - Present

#### **Associate I Software Developer**

- Contributor in Delivery team providing features, enhancements, defect fixes with comprehensive test suites using **Jmockit** and **Mockito** for existing **Spring Boot** Application
- Architected, designed and implemented a decoupled serverless service as an individual contributor in **Python** to facilitate trade forwarding deployed in AWS. Technologies involved includes **Lambda**, **S3**, **SQS** and **Terraform**.
- Implemented scripts and automations for internal operations in Bash, Python and Golang for development and support use cases. Some examples include implementation of a user creation script for trade reporting platform, reducing time cost by 75%, and automation for generating test cases, allowing up to 50% time saved in development.
- Architected, designed and built a standalone Spring Boot application independently to perform Extract, Transform, Load (ETL) across multiple financial instruments. Infrastructure and application components includes AWS EC2, S3 and RDS built with Terraform and GitLab CI for fully automated deployments.
- Provided time-critical root cause analysis, in-depth troubleshooting and resolution for existing Trade Reporting Platform as part of Level 2/3 Support team.

Handled numerous P1/P2 incidents, resolving issues reported by Level 1 Team and clients in accordance with trade reporting deadlines.

- Performed deep analysis and implemented solution on performance degradation due to memory leak in Spring Boot application, reducing operational time cost from 8 hours to 15 minutes
- Created and enhanced existing AWS infrastructure using Terraform and GitLab CI and transitioning of manually created resources to state-controlled resources with Terraform
- Developed and enhanced GitLab CI pipelines to streamline delivery and deployments processes, including codebase onboarding to static code analytical tools such as Mend and SonarQube
- Authoring technical designs and documentations for day 0 and day 2 operations for new and existing services
- Participated in Agile development cycles, acting as Scrum Master for development sprints on a rotational basis
- Executed and planned major migrations and exercises for clients with high data loads (over 80 million records).

#### Technologies & Languages used:

Springboot, Java, Cucumber, GitLab, Terraform, Linux, Shell, Bash, AWS, Python, JUnit, Cucumber

Autodesk Pte Ltd 2018-11 – 2019-10

# **Client Services Representative**

- Utilized existing CRM and ERP platforms to provide support and order taking for clients.
- Provided troubleshooting and issue resolution for the product through investigative work with clients ranging from distributors to end consumers

Pole to Win Singapore Pte Ltd

2016-01 - 2018-11

#### **Customer Support Team Lead**

- Spearheaded a small team of agents in daily operations. Liaised with Japanese clients for project objectives and targets. Did translations from English/Chinese to Japanese and vice versa.
- Removed human error and reduced time taken for operations by over 80% by implementing a Python script to extract data and manipulate data into the required format in Excel.
- Reduced time taken for workflow operations by over 30% through the implementing of scripts in Google App Script using Javascript.

# **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

### www.tatwritescode.com

Micro-blog/playground written in **Golang**, served using **Gin-gonic** on **AWS** while built using **Terraform**, **Docker**, and **Docker Compose** 

## **StudyBuddy**

<u>Mobile application</u> for flashcard-based studying with analytics for targeted learning built using **Flutter** 

# E-commerce Automation for www.theo10.com

Built a **Python** automation script that utilizes WooCommerce's API for order retrieving and data manipulation

# **OTHER SKILLS**

Japanese Langauge Proficiency Test - N1

2017-01

### **EDUCATION**

University of Wollongong

2019-01 - 2021-06

**Bachelor of Computer Science with Distinction, Big Data**